The Guide to the John Canemaker Animation Collection 1903-2012 (Bulk 1970-2000) MSS 040
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Audio & Video Tape Collection.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    - Lou Bunin, NYC, June 17, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40.0033)
    - Douglas Trumbull, Midwest Film Conference, Chicago, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 40.0034)
    - Gary Kurtz ( Star Wars Press Conference), May 24, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 40.0035)
    - Chuck Jones, guest on Dick Cavette television program, October 25, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 40.0036)
    - Willis Pyle, May 16, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 40.0037)
    - June Foray, NYC, October 14, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40.0038)
    - David Hilberman, Santa Cruz, CA, June 16, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 40.0039)
    - David Hilberman, Santa Cruz, CA., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 40.004)
    - Jules Engel, July 1, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 40.0041)
    - Peter Ellenshaw, lunch at Disney Studio, with Frank Thomas, Ollie Johnston, Joseph Kennedy, Chuck Richardson (Disney Public Relations), June 19, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 40.0042)
    - Side A: Stanley Sills, ITT, NYC, October 25, 1976; Side B: Elfriede Fischinger, May 6, 1977., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 40.0043)
    - John Canemaker reading from John Fitzsimmons' remembrances of Winsor McCay., undated (Box 1, Folder 40.0044)
      Audiocassette, Sony UX 60
    - Al Rezek and Tissa David, August 8, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 40.0045)
    - Pat Thackery, July 21, 1976; Tissa David, August 8, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 40.0046)
    - R.O. Blechman, NYC, July 14, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 40.0047)
    - Side A: Michael Sisson, July 15, 1976; Mike Sporn; Side B: Richard Williams, July 18, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 40.0048)
    - Susan Pitt, March 16, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 40.0049)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Otto Messmer (part of final interview), January 29, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.005)
      Audiocassette, Maxell UR 60
    - Al Eugster, May 12, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0051)
    - George Bakes on Bill Tytla, 1975. (Box 2, Folder 40.0052)
    - Adrienne Tytla (Bill Tytla's wife), Old Lyme, CT, April 11, 1975. (Box 2, Folder 40.0053)
    - Adrienne Tytla., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40.0054)
    - George Griffin, November 6, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 40.0055)
    - Paul Bray, Jr. (J.R. Bray's grandson), April 19, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 40.0056)
    - Milt Kahl at School of Visual Arts, with John Culhane, May 24, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 40.0057)
    - Milt Kahl at School of Visual Arts., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40.0058)
    - Ron Husband, Lorna Pomeroy, Dan Hansen, Jim Coleman, Pete Young, Steve Hulett, Dan Haskett, Jerry Rees, Bill Croyer, et al., Disney Studio, Burbank, CA, April 25, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 40.0059)
    - Side A: Disney Seminar at Lincoln Center (Film Society) with John Culhane, Frank Thomas, Ken Anderson, Woolie Reitherman, and Ken Anderson on character design and development, June 18, 1973; Side B: Frank Thomas on animation techniques. (Box 2, Folder 40.006)
    - Side A: Disney Seminar at Lincoln Center (Film Society) with Frank Thomas, Ken Anderson, and Woolie Reitherman; Side B: screening of television program The Plausible Impossible July 19, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 40.0061)
    - Frank Thomas on optical effects, July 19, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 40.0062)
    - Disney seminar on trainee program in animation., undated (Box 2, Folder 40.0063)
    - Zack Schwartz, NYC, September 12, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0064)
    - Zack Schwartz, NYC, September 12, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0065)
    - Zack Schwartz, September 18, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0066)
    - Zack Schwartz, September 18, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0067)
    - Fred Stuthman, Richard Horner, and Cozmo Anzillotti, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 6-9, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0068)
    - Jim Logan, Eric Goldberg, George Bakes, Cosmo Pepe, and Harry Chang, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 9-December 7, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0069)
    - Harry Chang, continued; Carol Millican, Dan Haskett, and Ida Greenberg, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 12-13, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.007)
    - Ida Greenberg, continued; Sue Butterworth, and Michael Sisson, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 15, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0071)
    - Hollywood Raggedy Ann studio; Hal Ambro, John Kimball and Corny Cole, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 26, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0072)
    - John Kimball, continued; Grim Natwick, and Art Babbitt, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 27, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 40.0073)
    - John Halas, London, November 5, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0074)
    - William Pomerance (on the Disney 1941 strike), April 17, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0075)
    - Joe Oriolo (on Felix the Cat), May 21, 1975. (Box 2, Folder 40.0076)
    - Joe Hambrook (on George Dunning and the BBC), November 25, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0077)
    - Richard Williams on George Dunning, November 20, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0078)
    - Art Babbitt, NYC, July 12, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0079)
    - Art Babbitt, NYC, July 12, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.008)
    - Douglas Leigh on Otto Messmer and electric sign work, April 19, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 40.0081)
    - Disney Studios: Art Stevens, Mel Shaw, Ed Hansen (on The Fox and Hound, Apri 16, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 40.0082)
    - Frank Thomas and Ollie Johnston, interview by Patricia McCann on WOR Radio, NYC, October 7, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 40.0083)
    - John Halas and Joy Batchelor en route to Cambridge, England, November 9, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0084)
    - Sally Cruikshank, June 11, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0085)
    - Sally Cruikshank (on Ruthless People titles; interview with Ted Wollery, August 7, 1986. (Box 2, Folder 40.0086)
      Audiocassette, Maxell C60
    - Independent Animators Interviews, conducted by Kit Laybourne for grant project [1979], including G. Griffin, Caroline Leaf, and John Canemaker. (Box 2, Folder 40.0087)
    - Independent Animators Interviews: G. Griffin, Caroline Leaf, and John Canemaker., [1979] (Box 2, Folder 40.0088)
    - David Tissa, May 29, 1973; George Dunning recorded from CBS Camera Three, May 20, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 40.0089)
    - John Canemaker interviewed by Radio Smithsonian, Washington, D.C., [1979]. (Box 2, Folder 40.009)
    - Fred Berner: final days of Raggedy Ann and Andy, 1977. (Box 2, Folder 40.0091)
    - Fred Berner: final days of Raggedy Ann and Andy, 1977. (Box 2, Folder 40.0092)
    - Frank Thomas and Ollie Johnston, interviewed by John Canemaker at the 1981 Midwest Film Conference, Chicago. (Box 2, Folder 40.0093)
    - Thomas and Johnston, 1981 Midwest Film Conference. (Box 2, Folder 40.0094)
    - John Canemaker lecture on early animation, Midwest Film Conference, February 13, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 40.0095)
    - Rudy Zamora, at Hanna-Barbera Studios, Los Angeles, June 21, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.0096)
    - Bob Clampett interviewed by John Canemaker at the Midwest Film Conference, February 13, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 40.0097)
    - Lecture by John Canemaker on early animators at the "Pioneers" -- LA Film Exposition, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 40.0098)
    - Interviews by John Canemaker of a panel of early animators, includign Grim Natwick, Walter Lantz, Rudy Isling, Richard Huemer, and Harry Love at the "History Makers" -- LA Film Exposition, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 40.0099)
    - Art Babbitt, recorded letter to John Canemaker, May 26, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 40.01)
  - Subseries B: Original recordings
    - J.R. Bray interview by John Canemaker; Bridgeport, CT.; March 25, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.0101)
      Audiocassette, TDK C-60
    - Art Babbitt remembers Bill Tytla in Los Angeles, March 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0102)
    - Art Babbitt interview by John Canemaker, New York City, June 4, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0103)
    - Art Babbitt interview by John Canemaker, New York City., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0104)
    - Side A: Ollie Johnston and Les Clark interviews, Disney Studio, Burbank, CA, July 5, 1973; Side B: Frank Thomas, Disney Studio, July 6, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 40.0105)
      Audiocassette, TDK C-60SD
    - Otto Messmer, Fort Lee, NJ, March 5, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 40.0106)
    - John A Fitzsimmons (Winsor McCay's assistant), Rockville Center, NY, September 22, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.0107)
    - Side A: Otto Messmer, March 5, 1975; Side B: George Bakes on Bill Tytla, NYC, March 11, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0108)
    - Shamus Culhane, NYC, February 13, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.0109)
    - Shamus Culhane, NYC, February 13, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.011)
    - Terri Gilliam (backstage City Center Theater), NYC, April 30, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 40.0111)
    - Emery Hawkins, NYC, January 12, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 40.0112)
      Audiocassette, TDK Maverick M C60
    - Otto Messmer (final interview, talks about early life, etc.), January 29, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0113)
      Audiocassette, Scotch C-60
    - Tex Hensen "remembers Walt Disney and Studio". Recorded in Dallas, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 40.0114)
      Audiocassette, Irish Series 2000-60
    - Bruno Bozzetto, NYC, February 12, 1979., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.0115)
      Audiocassette, Ampex Plus Series-60
    - George Dunning, Ottowa, Canada, Sept. 1, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 40.0116)
      Audiocassette, Ampex 361-C60
    - Side A: Don Duckwall; Side B: Eric Larson, Heidi Guedel, Emily Guliano, Walt Disney Studio, Burbank, CA, April 25, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 40.0117)
      Audiocassette, Recoton-ultra flow, 60
    - Len Lye, NYC, interviewed by Joseph Kennedy and John Canemaker, August 22, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 40.0118)
      Audiocassette, Scotch C-90
    - Side A: Len Lye, NYC; Side B: Walter Lantz, June 16, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 40.0119)
      Audiocassette, TDK C-90
    - Side A: Confessions of a Star Dreamer audio mix; Side B: Walter Lanz, June 16, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 40.012)
      Audiocassette, Sony C-60
    - Richard Williams, NYC, July 18, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 40.0121)
    - Side A: Richard Williams, NYC; Side B: Joe Raposo (on Raggedy Ann and Andy), July 19, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 40.0122)
    - Side A: David R. Smith, Disney Archives, Burbank, CA; Disney animation trainees, July 6, 1973; Side B: Ward Kimball, Arcadia, CA, July 7, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 40.0123)
    - Ward Kimball, Arcadia, CA, July 7, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 40.0124)
    - Harold Walker on Pat Sullivan, Otto Messmer, and Felix the Cat, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 40.0125)
      Audiocassette, Intermagnetics-90
    - Art Babbitt on Don Graham and Disney art school, February 21, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0126)
      Audiocassette, Racal-Zonal C-90
    - Frank Thomas answers list of questions, September 9, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 40.0127)
    - Grim Natwick, NYC, May 19, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.0128)
    - Richard Williams on Raggedy Ann and Andy, NYC, December 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0129)
    - Elfriede Fischinger and William Moritz interviewed by P. Adams Sitney on ArtForum, May 6, 1977., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40.013)
      Audiocassette, Memorex MRX2 Oxide, 60
    - George Griffin, NYC, September 5, 1985. (Box 3, Folder 40.0131)
    - Lou Bunin, NYC, June 3, 1986. (Box 3, Folder 40.0132)
    - Lou Bunin, NYC, June 17, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 40.0133)
    - Douglas Trumbull, Midwest Film Conference, Chicago, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 40.0134)
    - Gary Kurtz ( Star Wars Press Conference), May 24, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 40.0135)
    - Chuck Jones, guest on Dick Cavette television program, October 25, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0136)
    - Willis Pyle, May 16, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 40.0137)
    - June Foray, NYC, October 14, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40.0138)
    - David Hilberman, Santa Cruz, CA, June 16, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0139)
    - David Hilberman, Santa Cruz, CA., 1979 (Box 3, Folder 40.014)
    - Jules Engel, July 1, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 40.0141)
    - Peter Ellenshaw, lunch at Disney Studio, with Frank Thomas, Ollie Johnston, Joseph Kennedy, Chuck Richardson (Disney Public Relations), June 19, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0142)
    - Side A: Stanley Sills, ITT, NYC, October 25, 1976; Side B: Elfriede Fischinger, May 6, 1977., 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 40.0143)
    - John Canemaker reading from John Fitzsimmons' remembrances of Winsor McCay., undated (Box 3, Folder 40.0144)
    - Al Rezek and Tissa David, August 8, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 40.0145)
    - Pat Thackery, July 21, 1976; Tissa David, August 8, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 40.0146)
    - R.O. Blechman, NYC, July 14, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 40.0147)
    - Side A: Michael Sisson, July 15, 1976; Mike Sporn; Side B: Richard Williams, July 18, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 40.0148)
    - Susan Pitt, March 16, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.0149)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Otto Messmer (part of final interview), January 29, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 40.015)
    - Al Eugster, May 12, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0151)
    - George Bakes on Bill Tytla, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 40.0152)
    - Adrienne Tytla (Bill Tytla's wife), Old Lyme, CT, April 11, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 40.0153)
    - Adrienne Tytla., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 40.0154)
    - George Griffin, November 6, 1974. (Box 4, Folder 40.0155)
    - Paul Bray, Jr. (J.R. Bray's grandson), April 19, 1974. (Box 4, Folder 40.0156)
    - Milt Kahl at School of Visual Arts, with John Culhane, May 24, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 40.0157)
    - Milt Kahl at School of Visual Arts., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 40.0158)
    - Ron Husband, Lorna Pomeroy, Dan Hansen, Jim Coleman, Pete Young, Steve Hulett, Dan Haskett, Jerry Rees, Bill Croyer, et al., Disney Studio, Burbank, CA, April 25, 1978. (Box 4, Folder 40.0159)
    - Side A: Disney Seminar at Lincoln Center (Film Society) with John Culhane, Frank Thomas, Ken Anderson, Woolie Reitherman, and Ken Anderson on character design and development, June 18, 1973; Side B: Frank Thomas on animation techniques. (Box 4, Folder 40.016)
    - Side A: Disney Seminar at Lincoln Center (Film Society) with Frank Thomas, Ken Anderson, and Woolie Reitherman; Side B: screening of television program The Plausible Impossible July 19, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 40.0161)
    - Frank Thomas on optical effects, July 19, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 40.0162)
    - Disney seminar on trainee program in animation., undated (Box 4, Folder 40.0163)
    - Zack Schwartz, NYC, September 12, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0164)
    - Zack Schwartz, NYC, September 12, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0165)
    - Zack Schwartz, September 18, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0166)
    - Zack Schwartz, September 18, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0167)
    - Fred Stuthman, Richard Horner, and Cozmo Anzillotti, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 6-9, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0168)
    - Jim Logan, Eric Goldberg, George Bakes, Cosmo Pepe, and Harry Chang, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 9-December 7, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0169)
    - Harry Chang, continued; Carol Millican, Dan Haskett, and Ida Greenberg, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 12-13, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.017)
    - Ida Greenberg, continued; Sue Butterworth, and Michael Sisson, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 15, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0171)
    - Hollywood Raggedy Ann studio; Hal Ambro, John Kimball and Corny Cole, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 26, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0172)
    - John Kimball, continued; Grim Natwick, and Art Babbitt, interviewed as part of research for John Canemaker's 1977 book, The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy, July 27, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 40.0173)
    - John Halas, London, November 5, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0174)
    - William Pomerance (on the Disney 1941 strike), April 17, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0175)
    - Joe Oriolo (on Felix the Cat), May 21, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 40.0176)
    - Joe Hambrook (on George Dunning and the BBC), November 25, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0177)
    - Richard Williams on George Dunning, November 20, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0178)
    - Art Babbitt, NYC, July 12, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0179)
    - Art Babbitt, NYC, July 12, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.018)
    - Douglas Leigh on Otto Messmer and electric sign work, April 19, 1984. (Box 4, Folder 40.0181)
    - Disney Studios: Art Stevens, Mel Shaw, Ed Hansen (on The Fox and Hound, Apri 16, 1981. (Box 4, Folder 40.0182)
    - Frank Thomas and Ollie Johnston, interview by Patricia McCann on WOR Radio, NYC, October 7, 1981. (Box 4, Folder 40.0183)
    - John Halas and Joy Batchelor en route to Cambridge, England, November 9, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0184)
    - Sally Cruikshank, June 11, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0185)
    - Sally Cruikshank (on Ruthless People titles; interview with Ted Wollery, August 7, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 40.0186)
    - Independent Animators Interviews, conducted by Kit Laybourne for grant project [1979], including G. Griffin, Caroline Leaf, and John Canemaker. (Box 4, Folder 40.0187)
    - Independent Animators Interviews: G. Griffin, Caroline Leaf, and John Canemaker., [1979] (Box 4, Folder 40.0188)
    - David Tissa, May 29, 1973; George Dunning recorded from CBS Camera Three, May 20, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 40.0189)
    - John Canemaker interviewed by Radio Smithsonian, Washington, D.C., [1979]. (Box 4, Folder 40.019)
    - Fred Berner: final days of Raggedy Ann and Andy, 1977. (Box 4, Folder 40.0191)
    - Fred Berner: final days of Raggedy Ann and Andy, 1977. (Box 4, Folder 40.0192)
    - Frank Thomas and Ollie Johnston, interviewed by John Canemaker at the 1981 Midwest Film Conference, Chicago. (Box 4, Folder 40.0193)
    - Thomas and Johnston, 1981 Midwest Film Conference. (Box 4, Folder 40.0194)
    - John Canemaker lecture on early animation, Midwest Film Conference, February 13, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 40.0195)
    - Rudy Zamora, at Hanna-Barbera Studios, Los Angeles, June 21, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.0196)
    - Bob Clampett interviewed by John Canemaker at the Midwest Film Conference, February 13, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 40.0197)
    - Lecture by John Canemaker on early animators at the "Pioneers" -- LA Film Exposition, 1978. (Box 4, Folder 40.0198)
    - Interviews by John Canemaker of a panel of early animators, including Grim Natwick, Walter Lantz, Rudy Isling, Richard Huemer, and Harry Love at the "History Makers" -- LA Film Exposition, 1978. (Box 4, Folder 40.0199)
    - Art Babbitt, recorded letter to John Canemaker, May 26, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 40.02)
  - Subseries C: Preservation Masters
    - Art Babbitt, interview at his room in the NY Sheridan Hotel during a visit to attend pre-production meetings for Raggedy Ann and Andy, recorded June 4, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 40.0201)
      1/4" reel to reel, Concertape, 7" reel.
    - Side A: Interview with John Bray recorded at 94 year-old Bray's apartment in Bridgeport, CT; Side B: Art Babbitt on Bill Tytla, recorded by Babbitt in his Hollywood home on March 18, 1975 in response to written questions sent by Canemaker who was gathering material for a 1976 CineFantastic magazine article on Tytla. (Box 5, Folder 40.0202)
    - Side A: Frank Thomas, Ollie Johnston, and Les Clark, three of Disney's top animators, recorded during Canemakers's first visit to the Disney Studio in Burbank on July 6, 1973; Side B: Interview with Otto Messmer about Felix the Cat in his home in Fort Lee, NJ on March 5, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 40.0203)
    - Side A: Interview with John Fitzsimmons, Winsor McCay's assistant on Gertie the Dinosaur(1914), and Sinking of the Lusitania(1918) recorded September 22, 1974 in his home in Rockville Centre, NY; Side B: Continuation of the 1975 interview with Otto Messmer, George Bakes also present and discusses Bill Tytla's genius and his own biographical information. (Box 5, Folder 40.0204)
    - Shamus Culhane, who animated the dwarfs marching home in Snow White, and owned one of the earliest and most successful TV commercial studios discusses his career, recorded at his NYC apartment on February 13, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 40.0205)
    - Interview with Terry Gilliam, animator for Monty Python's Flying Circus, recorded backstage at City Center, NYC during Python's Broadway run, April 30, 1976. (Box 5, Folder 40.0206)
    - Side A: Otto Messmer, and his wife Anne Messmer, interviewed in their NJ home about his early years, recorded on January 29, 1979; Side B: Tex Hensen interview recorded near his home in Dallas, talks about his work for Disney. (Box 5, Folder 40.0207)
    - Side A: Bruno Bozzetto interviewed at Italtoons office in NYC on February 12, 1979; Side B: Interview with George Dunning recorded in September 1978, in his hotel room in Ottawa during the Ottawa Animation Festival. This is the last interview Dunning gave before his death in March 1979., 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 40.0208)
    - Side A: Interview with Don Duckwall, Animation Production Manager at Disney Studio, and veteran animator Eric Larson discuss the new animation training program at Disney, recorded April 25, 1978; Side B: Len Lye, speaks with John Canemaker and Joseph Kennedy and shows a slide presentation of his work with a recorded track outlining his artistic philosophy, recorded August 22, 1976., 1976; 1978 (Box 5, Folder 40.0209)
    - Interview with Len Lye continues; part 2 of an interview with Walter Lantz during his visit to NYC for a tribute at MoMA, recorded June 16, 1977., 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 40.021)
    - Side A: Interview with Richard Williams recorded in NYC during the production of Raggedy Ann and Andy on July 18, 1976; Side B: Richard Williams continued; interview with Joe Raposo, composer of score for Raggedy Ann and Andy, recorded July 19, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 40.0211)
    - Interviews with the first group of young Disney animation trainees at the studio in Burbank; David Smith, Disney archivist, interviewed in his office, July 6, 1973; interview with Ward Kimball, Disney animator and avid collector of toy trains, July 7, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 40.0212)
    - Side A: Harold Walker, one of the few surviving members of the Felix the Cat (Pat Sullivan) Studio, interviewed in 1978 by his son at his retirement home; Side B: Art Babbitt recorded response to a Millimeter (February 1978) article on Don Graham written by Canemaker. (Box 5, Folder 40.0213)
    - Frank Thomas response to questions from Canemaker written for research for a magazine article, September 8, 1974; Side B: Grim Natwick interview conducted in NYC on May 19, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 40.0214)
    - Richard Williams interview for a 1976 article for Millimeter magazine during the beginning of the Raggedy Ann production; Side B: Elfriede Fischinger and William Moritz speak on a radio program conducted by P. Adams Sitney about the films and life of Oscar Fischinger, May 6, 1977., 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 40.0215)
- Oversize: Series I: Documentary Material
  - Subseries B: People
    - Disney, Walt: FANTASIA, SONG OF THE SOUTH, SUMMER MAGIC, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Kinney, Jack: Galleys of "Walt Disney & Other Assorted Characters", undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Disney, Walt: AnimationArt Calendar, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Disney, Walt: FANTASIA, undated (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Jones, Chuck - Artwork, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Tex Avery, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Oversize: Series II: Graphic Material
  - Subseries B: Posters
    NOTE: () denotes the number of posters
    - AbbevilleCelebrates the Real McCay (2), undated (Box [map case], Folder 1)
    - Animated World of John Canemaker, 1979 (3) (Box [map case], Folder 2)